<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>onchaingang on 6120's Notes</title><link>https://6120.eu/tags/onchaingang/</link><description>Recent content in onchaingang on 6120's Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright/><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 13:22:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://6120.eu/tags/onchaingang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>{In,On}Chain discussion</title><link>https://6120.eu/posts/in-on-chain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 13:22:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://6120.eu/posts/in-on-chain/</guid><description>In the rapidly evolving realm of Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs), distinguishing between &amp;ldquo;inchain&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;onchain&amp;rdquo; is crucial for understanding how digital artworks are stored and processed within the blockchain ecosystem. This article delves into the nuanced differences between these two concepts, shedding light on their implications for NFT artwork and its interaction with blockchain technology.
Inchain vs. Onchain: Definitions and Distinctions In-Chain refers to data that is both stored and processed on the blockchain.</description><content>&lt;p>In the rapidly evolving realm of Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs), distinguishing between &amp;ldquo;inchain&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;onchain&amp;rdquo; is crucial for understanding how digital artworks are stored and processed within the blockchain ecosystem. This article delves into the nuanced differences between these two concepts, shedding light on their implications for NFT artwork and its interaction with blockchain technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="inchain-vs-onchain-definitions-and-distinctions">Inchain vs. Onchain: Definitions and Distinctions&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In-Chain refers to data that is both stored and processed on the blockchain. When applied to NFT artwork, this means that the media is processed into its displayable form by the blockchain&amp;rsquo;s first execution layer, such as the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM) for Ethereum. This process ensures that the artwork does not require Turing complete processing after the initial onchain execution, making it directly observable from the blockchain without additional postchain processing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On-Chain, in contrast, pertains to data that is stored on the blockchain but processed offchain. This means that while the media is stored within the blockchain, the actual rendering and processing of the artwork occur offchain, often in real-time and using external technologies like JavaScript. NFTs that necessitate such Post-Chain Processing (PCP) include those that are displayed or interacted with through browsers, desktop applications, or games.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="challenges-and-considerations">Challenges and Considerations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Selecting the appropriate level of inchain versus onchain processing for a specific media type involves navigating multiple challenges. These include considering the media&amp;rsquo;s format (e.g., raster image, interactive vector image, sound) and the processing capabilities required at each layer (EVM to JavaScript, Equalizer, etc.). The decision hinges on the unique requirements and constraints of each use case, aiming to strike a balance between onchain storage efficiency and offchain processing flexibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Differentiating between pure SVG/HTML and Turing-complete languages highlights a conceptual challenge due to the inherent nature of SVG (Scalable Vector Graphics) and HTML (HyperText Markup Language) as descriptive languages, rather than computational or programming languages. SVG and HTML are fundamentally designed to describe the layout, structure, and presentation of content on the web, lacking the ability to perform arbitrary computations or algorithmic processes that define Turing completeness. This distinction becomes blurred when considering the interactive and dynamic capabilities that can be embedded within SVG and HTML documents through the use of JavaScript and CSS. While SVG and HTML alone do not possess the computational capabilities to be considered Turing complete, their integration with scripting languages enables them to support complex interactions and behaviors, making it difficult to separate their descriptive nature from the potential for Turing-complete operations facilitated by external scripts. This complexity underscores the challenge in categorizing SVG and HTML strictly as non-Turing-complete languages, especially in the context of modern web applications where the lines between content description and computational logic increasingly intersect.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="media-types-and-post-chain-processing">Media Types and Post-Chain Processing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The following table highlights various media types and their requirements for Post-Chain Processing (PCP):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Media types with Post-Chain Processing:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Media&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Audio&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Image&lt;/th>
&lt;th>PCP&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Example&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Comments&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BMP_file_format">BMP&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://opensea.io/fr/assets/ethereum/0x23581767a106ae21c074b2276d25e5c3e136a68b/8173">MoonBirds&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://opensea.io/assets/ethereum/0x46d0d00e847ed9c2756cfd941e70d99e9152a22f/0">ReaperGambitEpitaph&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Stored on Ethereum mainnet&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GIF#File_format">GIF&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n/a&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n/a&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://www.khronos.org/assets/uploads/developers/library/overview/gltf-overview.pdf">GLTF&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>?&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://www.ord.io/489270">SkyLight&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Bitcoin Ordinal 489270&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JPEG#Syntax_and_structure">JPG&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n/a&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n/a&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MP4_file_format#Data_streams">MP4&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>?&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n/a&lt;/td>
&lt;td>May contains multiple media streams&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WAV#">WAV&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://opensea.io/assets/ethereum/0x9d27527ada2cf29fbdab2973cfa243845a08bd3f/405">Bleeps&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Onchain sound note&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ogg#">OGG&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_Media_Markup_Language">X&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n/a&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n/a&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML#">HTML&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://ordinals.com/content/521f8eccffa4c41a3a7728dd012ea5a4a02feed81f41159231251ecf1e5c79dai0">Yet Another Doom Clone&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Ordinal 466&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SVG">SVG&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SVG_animation">X&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n/a&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n/a&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>These examples underscore the versatility and potential of inchain NFTs for ensuring compatibility across various devices and platforms, opening new avenues for interactive and dynamic artwork creation via smart contracts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="costs">Costs&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Inchain data insertion typically incurs lower costs compared to onchain methods due to the ability to leverage RPC provider execution to optimize the final artwork. The specifics of cost reduction may vary across different implementations. Additionally, storage maintenance is often provided at no additional cost on most blockchains.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conversely, offchain storage solutions are significantly more cost-effective but require ongoing maintenance. Over an extended period, these maintenance expenses can accumulate, potentially surpassing the initial cost savings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The distinction between inchain and onchain NFTs lies at the heart of how digital artworks are stored, processed, and experienced within the blockchain framework. While inchain NFTs offer a seamless experience without the need for additional processing, onchain NFTs provide a canvas for more complex and interactive artworks, albeit with the requirement for external processing resources. As the NFT landscape continues to evolve, understanding these nuances becomes paramount for creators, collectors, and technologists alike.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="future-work---nft-dynamism">Future work - NFT Dynamism&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>NFT can be interactive and evolve, here is a mind map laying out the disambiugation work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click &lt;a href="https://viewer.diagrams.net/index.html?target=blank&amp;amp;highlight=0000ff&amp;amp;nav=1&amp;amp;title=Dynamic%20NFT%20disambiguation.drawio#Uhttps%3A%2F%2Fdrive.google.com%2Fuc%3Fid%3D1EKwLBN6kVsxHzujLLU3eX9c4ReQ2EUXX%26export%3Ddownload">here&lt;/a> if you have trouble navigating the document.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe frameborder="0" style="min-width:1024px; min-height:768px; width:1024px;height:768px;" src="https://viewer.diagrams.net/?target=blank&amp;highlight=0000ff&amp;nav=1&amp;title=Dynamic%20NFT%20disambiguation.drawio#Uhttps%3A%2F%2Fdrive.google.com%2Fuc%3Fid%3D1EKwLBN6kVsxHzujLLU3eX9c4ReQ2EUXX%26export%3Ddownload">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>More ressources:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://onchainchecker.xyz/">On-Chain Checker&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.simondlr.com/posts/flavours-of-on-chain-svg-nfts-on-ethereum">Simon de la Rouviere&amp;rsquo;s Flavours of on-chain SVG blog post&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.fullyonchain.art/">Discover On-Chain NFT Projects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>In on Chain</title><link>https://6120.eu/drafts/in-on-chain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 02:30:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://6120.eu/drafts/in-on-chain/</guid><description>In-chain refers to something that is stored and processed on the blockchain, while on-chain refers to something that is stored on the blockchain but processed off-chain. In the case of NFT artwork, in-chain would refer to the media being processed to its final form by the first execution layer, such as the EVM in Ethereum. On-chain would refer to the media being stored on the blockchain, but the processing and rendering of the artwork happens off-chain using JavaScript, for example, in real-time.</description><content>&lt;p>In-chain refers to something that is stored and processed on the blockchain, while on-chain refers to something that is stored on the blockchain but processed off-chain. In the case of NFT artwork, in-chain would refer to the media being processed to its final form by the first execution layer, such as the EVM in Ethereum. On-chain would refer to the media being stored on the blockchain, but the processing and rendering of the artwork happens off-chain using JavaScript, for example, in real-time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some media formats, such as SVG, contain multiple data streams that may require different levels of processing, it can be rendered using rasterization techniques, but it can also be enhanced with CSS and/or JavaScript. This means that some parts of the image may be processed in-chain, while others may be processed off-chain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, depending on the context, the final form of the media may be different, it can be a raster image or a interactive vector image, so the processing can be different for each context and each final form. This can make it challenging to determine the appropriate level of in-chain and off-chain processing for certain types of media, and may require careful consideration of the specific requirements and constraints of the use case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus we can define in-chain NFT where the artwork does not require* turing complete processing post first on-chain execution (e.g: when tokenURI function return embbed audio/video in metadatas)
(as in mandatory). The processing capability being brought by the human user, and therefore, a NFT can be considered in-chain when it does not require post-chain processing, for example, in wallets, twitter profile pictures, and so on. On the other hand, NFTs that require Post-Chain Processing(PCP), for example, in browsers, desktop apps, or games, are considered on-chain NFTs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example of possible artwork media types with possible Post-Chain Processing:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Media&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Audio&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Image&lt;/th>
&lt;th>PCP&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audio_Video_Interleave#">AVI&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BMP_file_format">BMP&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GIF#File_format">GIF&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GlTF#GLB">GLB&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://www.khronos.org/assets/uploads/developers/library/overview/gltf-overview.pdf">GLTF&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JPEG#Syntax_and_structure">JPG&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MP4_file_format#Data_streams">MP4&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WAV#">WAV&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebM#">WebM&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ogg#">OGG&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_Media_Markup_Language">X&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML#">HTML&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SVG">SVG&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SVG_animation">X&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Examples projects by media type:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Add OpenSea Link&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In-chain BMP NFT is &lt;a href="https://etherscan.deth.net/address/0xd31fc221d2b0e0321c43e9f6824b26ebfff01d7d#code">Brotchain&lt;/a> NFT processing image&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In-chain WAV NFT is the &lt;a href="https://etherscan.deth.net/address/0xE114DCe59A333f8D351371F54188F92C287b73E6#code">Bleeps&lt;/a> NFT Waveform synthetizer&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>(It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that the table is not an exhaustive list of all media types that can be used for NFT artwork)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The concept of in-chain and on-chain NFTs refers to the storage and processing of digital artwork on the blockchain by smart-contracts following NFT standards. In-chain NFTs are those where the artwork does not require Post-Chain Processing and can be viewed using standard software or hardware. On the other hand, on-chain NFTs require post-chain processing, such as in browsers or desktop apps. The broad spectrum of possibilities for In-chain NFTs allows for greater compatibility across devices and opens up unexplored possibilities for on-chain computation, such as the ability to create more interactive and dynamic artwork, or the ability to use smart contracts to create unique, one-of-a-kind pieces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INSERT DIAGRAM from DRAW.IO&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NB: We could use the &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2109.14534.pdf">StarkNet Cairo CPU&lt;/a> intercheangibly with the EVM as long as the smart-contract follows NFT standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More ressources:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.simondlr.com/posts/flavours-of-on-chain-svg-nfts-on-ethereum">Simon de la Rouviere&amp;rsquo;s Flavours of on-chain SVG blog post&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>